Michael Stokley

Seattle, WA

(303) 801-8575 • ⋈ michael@michaelstokley.com • ⋈ michaelstokley.com • in mastokley mastokley

Profile

Software developer. I'm patient enough to take difficult projects seriously, and driven enough to automate tedious, needlessly manual work. In my previous accounting position, I greatly exceeded expectations by learning SQL to automate data entry / data quality work (and avoid using a cumbersome GUI). Since then, I have spent two years studying math, computer science, and statistics at North Seattle College, attended Code Fellows' Python Development Intensive (taught by esteemed pythonista Cris Ewing). I've been working as a foundational member of the engineering team at iDatalabs, building out a customer facing web portal with Vue.js, Flask, and PostgreSQL. My goals for 2018: learn more diverse languages (e. g. functional, typed, low-level, or systems); learn to handle asynchrony without callbacks (e.g. channels found in Go or Clojure); blog about design patterns; work through a few more chapters of SICP.

Technical Skills

Proficient Familiar

Python, Django, Flask, PostgreSQL, JavaScript/HTML/CSS, Vue.js, Webpack, AWS, Heroku, Ansible, Nginx, Gunicorn, MongoDB, Pyra-Git, SQL, Unix, MVC, HTTP, OOP, FP, Highcharts

mid, Scheme, Clojure

Experience

Full Stack Engineer

iDatalabs, Bellevue, WA 2017.01 - 2017.10

I owned (built, maintained, and took full responsibility for) a Vue.js single page application that displays and sells marketing data; I maintained and updated the consumed api (written in Flask) and updated underlying db schema to fit api requirements as needed. I worked on all tiers of the architecture, from UI to backend, to our Postgres and Mongo databases, to the various Apache and Nginx servers deployed across Azure instances.

- O Designed and implemented a 'store' to manage client-side shared state using Vuex
- o Optimized perceived page performance, including both frontend and backend optimizations
- Knocked up internal admin dashboards in Flask as needed for Sales, Marketing, Analytics

Freelance Web Developer

Red Mountain Software. Seattle. WA

2016.08 - 2016.10

Designed, built, and tested an internal management application according to client specification. Thoughtfully designed and implemented db schema to fit domain-specific business objects. App built with Django and PostgreSQL with jQuery on the front as needed.

Co-founding Software Developer

Sternshus, Inc., Seattle, WA 2016.07 - 2016.09

Provided frontend solutions in the context of rapidly changing business requirements. Worked primarily in Webflow, Django, and MySQL. I am most proud of having written sed and python scripts to automate merging Webflow files into the larger Django project.

AR Specialist

Cleanscapes, Seattle, WA 2012.04 - 2015.04

Wrote and maintained a library of accurate, sophisticated SQL queries to capture evolving data inconsistencies; these queries eliminated 37.5 labor hours per month despite a 126% increase in customer accounts over a two year period

Projects

Nord Entities

michaelstokley.com/Projects/nord-entities

2016.10

Literate programming exploration of natural language processing techniques such as tokenizing, chunking, and named entity recognition. Written in Python with Requests, the NLTK, and Beautiful Soup.

Twitter Haiku

michaelstokley.com/Projects/twitter-haiku

2016.06

Literate programming exercise in web scraping, tokenizing, and functional programming techniques learned from the SICP. Written in Python.

Toy Domain Scraper

michaelstokley.com/Projects/toy-domain-scraper

2016.04

Toy web scraper built in Python. Uses breadth-first traversal for fast, reliable results.

Education

Code Fellows Seattle, WA

Certificate

Advanced Python development emphasizing test driven development, pair programming, agile methodologies, version control, and basic data structures and algorithms

Seattle, WA North Seattle College

Coursework in Math, Computer Science, and Statistics

2012-2014

St. John's College Annapolis, MD B. A. in Philosophy 2009